DESPOINA TOUSKA

d3py.tousk@gmail.com \leq Linkedin \leq ORCID \leq Google Scolar \leq Webpage

PROFILE

Software engineer with 2+ years of experience as a research associate in the machine learning and computer vision fields. Posses abilities to identify, understand and translate program requirements into sustainable, advanced technical solutions through Python, C, C++, JavaScript, and other programs for continuous improvement of AI technologies.

EDUCATION

Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

Thessaloniki, Greece

MSc in Electrical and Computer Engineering

October 2013 - April 2020

• Cumulative GPA: 8.35/10

• Relevant Coursework: Pattern Recognition, Parallel & Distributed Systems, Probabilities & Statistics, Data Structures, Structured Programming, Robotics, Database Systems

Centre for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH)

Thessaloniki, Greece

Collaboration for thesis completion

November 2018 - September 2019

• Thesis: Video Forgery Detection using Autoencoder and Recurrent Neural Networks (link)

• Grade: 10/10

EXPERIENCE

Centre for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH)

Thessaloniki, Greece

Machine Learning Engineer and Research Associate

September 2020 - Present

- Contributed to scientific papers published on conferences and workshops.
- Developed and integrated machine learning system lifecycles utilizing cutting-edge open-source technologies for object detection, object tracking, and activity recognition.

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto (ISEP)

Porto, Portugal

Software Engineer and Research Intern

October 2019 - February 2020

- Collected and prepared video data of hand gestures.
- Developed a prototype web application to train and predict the translation of sign language videos to text.

Centre for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH)

Thessaloniki, Greece

Software Engineer and Research Intern

March 2018 - May 2018

- Contributed to the research for a multimedia forensics scientific paper.
- Developed and evaluated machine learning models for computer vision and natural language processing tasks.

INDICATIVE PUBLICATIONS

- D. Touska, K. Gkountakos, K. Ioannidis, T. Tsikrika, S. Vrochidis, I. Kompatsiaris. *Graph-Based Data Association in Multiple Object Tracking: A Survey.* MMM2023. 2023.
- Gkountakos, K., **Touska**, **D.**, Ioannidis, K., Tsikrika, T., Vrochidis, S., & Kompatsiaris, I. Spatio-temporal activity detection and recognition in untrimmed surveillance videos. ICMR. 2021.
- Gkountakos, K., Galanopoulos, D., **Touska, D.**, Ioannidis, K., Vrochidis, S., Mezaris, V., & Kompatsiaris, I. ITI-CERTH participation in ActEV and AVS Tracks of TRECVID 2021. TRECVID. 2021.
- Zampoglou, M., Markatopoulou, F., Mercier, G., **Touska, D.**, Apostolidis, E., Papadopoulos, S., ... & Kompatsiaris, I. Detecting tampered videos with multimedia forensics and deep learning. MMM2019. 2019.

SKILLS

Languages: English (fluent, C2, IELTS: 7.5/9), Greek (native), German (beginner, A2).

Programming Languages: Python (advanced), C/C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL.

Libraries: PyTorch, Keras, Tensorflow, TensorFlow.js, OpenCV, NumPy, Pandas, Sci-Kit Learn.

Production Tools: Docker, Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ, Git.